# **ANNE-LAURE FRÉANT**

Technical writer

# **BACKGROUND**

With 10 years of experience in the digital industry, for innovative startup in Canada as well as french state-level institutions (ministers & Prime Minister Services), I have gained a wide set of skills as a technical writer, content writer and UX writer. I am looking for freelance opportunities to work for ambitious companies or startups to grow for the next years, preferably in an innovative environment where autonomy and continuous-learning are valued.

# SKILLS

- Technical writing: software and API documentation and guides
- Knowledge base, Confluence
- Markdown, HTML 5, CSS
- Basic knowledge of Javascript
- Github, GitPages
- CMS (Wordpress)
- Static sites (Jekyll, Docusaurus)
- · Agile methods
- JIRA, Notion, Trello, Slack
- Google suite,
- Adobe Illustrator (for diagrams)
- Suite Office
- Research and technology watch
- Bilingual english-french (TEFL certification for Teaching English as a Foreign Language): TOEIC score 975

# **CERTIFICATES**

- "API Technical Writing" (Udemy course), to obtained in 2022
- -"Contentsquare Expert" (certification obtained in 2022)

## CONTACT

Cell: +33 7 81 85 42 73

Email: annelaure.freant@gmail.com

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Freelance technical writer (June 2021 - now)

Remote from France / Paris region

- I conduct technical writing long-term missions for e-commerce and data analytics innovative start-ups (Quantic Factory, Djust), building user guides, updating & restructuring existing documentation, and writing newsletters and release notes when needed.
- I also provide consulting services regarding knowledge management and documentation management internally.

# Technical writer & Product Knowledge Manager (Sept. 2022-Fev.2023) Paris - Contentsquare (full time contract)

• I joined the Knowledge Management Team and was in charge of a part of the product's internal knowledge base in Confluence. I updated and wrote the documentation (product foundations: APIs, data pipeline, back-office), and managed internal release communications (Slack and emails).

### Technical writer (Full time contract. Jan. 2020 - Aug. 2020) Etalab, French Prime Minister Services (Paris)

• Within the team in charge of the open data platform data.gouv.fr, I worked as a technical writer on both data.gouv.fr documentation and content pages of the platform itself (datasets description and listing). Part of the job also involved some editorial project management (editorial planning, social media).

### Technical & UX writer (Consultant from Jan. 2016 to Dec. 2020)

French Ministry of Foreign Affairs (Paris)

As the founder of a website about reentry in France (retourenfrance.fr), I
became the UX writer and information architect for the creation of an online
public service. I designed the matrix of rules and conditions and handled
editorial maintenance for 4 years.

### Technical Content Team Lead (Jan. 2011 - Dec. 2014)

Hopper.com (Montreal & Boston)

• I entered the company as a part-time data entry specialist. After 6 months I was offered to take the lead of the content team (reporting directly to CEO), and a year later I was offered to take the lead of Hopper's research and innovation blog as an editorial project manager.

### Research & Teaching assistant (full time contract, 2008-2011)

Geography department, University of Quebec in Montreal (Montreal)

• Teaching and assisting the Pr. M. Bédard with research seminars and lectures.

# **EDUCATION**

Sciencespo Paris - Post-Master degree, School of Public Affairs Sept. 2020 - June 2021

University of Quebec in Montreal (UQAM)- Master degree in Geography Sept. 2006 - June 2008